Guide to the Stanford University, Program in Human Biology, Middle Schools Curriculum Project, Videorecordings and Computer Files
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Program in Human Biology, Middle Schools Curriculum Project, videorecordings and computer files
1988-1996
SC0775
Stanford University. Program in Human Biology. Middle Schools Curriculum Project
2.5 Linear feet
Collection includes the video program Human Biology for the Middle Grades: A Bold New Approach, 1988; videotapes of team presentations from the Summer Institute of 1993; one video tape from the Summer Institute of 1991; other miscellaneous video tapes; CD-ROM of the program's instructional unit on the heart and lungs; other CD-ROMs; and floppy disks and hard drives containing the texts for publication.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Middle Schools Curriculum Project began in 1987 with the intent to develop a science curriculum that would interest many diverse students and give them a solid knowledge base. A prototype based on the Human Biology curriculum at Stanford was so successful that that focus was continued. From 1991 to 1994 Summer Institutes were held at Stanford with teachers and administrators from 12 diverse test-site middle schools.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes the video program Human Biology for the Middle Grades: A Bold New Approach, 1988; videotapes of team presentations from the Summer Institute of 1993; one video tape from the Summer Institute of 1991; other miscellaneous video tapes; CD-ROM of the program's instructional unit on the heart and lungs; other CD-ROMs; and floppy disks and hard drives containing the texts for publication.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Program in Human Biology. Middle Schools Curriculum Project; Biology--Study and teaching (Elementary).
Collection Contents
- Videorecordings and Computer Files, 1988-1996
  - Human Biology Middle School Project – Summer Institute 1993, 9 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - HumBio Institute – Activities, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Human Biology for the Middle Grades: A Bold New Approach (dub of master) 2/16/1989, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Human Biology for the Middle Grades: A Bold New Approach (dub) 9/20/1988, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Stanford University HUMBIO Multimedia Prototype Demo, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - HumBio – Middle Grades 1992, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Summer Institute 1993 – "Where do we go from here?" session 7/28/1993; Candid Club Shots, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Program in Human Biology, Summer Institute 1991: Middle Earth Club; McKown 725-0334, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Howard Hughes Medical Institute Holiday Lecture Series, 12/9-12/10/1996 – Lectures 1-4, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Anson Jones Award, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Programs, 1 optical disc (CD-ROM) (Box 3)
  - Floppy disks and hard drives (text for publications) (Box 3)
  - Videos not produced by the program (Box 3)